http://www.metabolomicssociety.org/privacy-policy

HomeBoard & CommitteesBoard of DirectorsPrevious Directors of the Metabolomics SocietySociety CommitteesConference CommitteeTraining CommitteeEarly-career Members Network (EMN) CommitteeMembership CommitteeNominations & Election CommitteePublications CommitteeWebsite and Communications CommitteeScientific Task GroupsData Quality Task GroupData Standards Task GroupMetabolite Identification Task GroupComputational Mass Spectrometry Task GroupModel Organism Metabolomes Task GroupPrecision Medicine and Pharmacometabolomics Task GroupOther Society Task GroupsInternational Affiliations Task GroupIndustry Engagement Task GroupSociety Strategy Task GroupPublicationsNewslettersTraining Needs in MetabolomicsEventsUpcoming Conferences and WorkshopsPast Society ConferencesPast ConferencesEvent FundingResourcesBylawsTutorialsMetabolomics ForumMetabolomics DatabasesMetabolomics SoftwareMetabolomics StandardsMultimediaJobsAwardsStudent AwardsEarly Career AwardsPublication AwardsOther AwardsHonorary FellowshipsMetabolomics Society Career MedalsMembers CenterBecome a MemberEarly-career Members NetworkCorporate MembersBenefits of MembershipCurrent Members2018 Corporate Members2017 Corporate Members2016 Corporate Members2015 Corporate Members2014 Corporate Members2013 Corporate Members2012 Corporate MembersInternational AffiliationsBenefits of AffiliationCurrent AffiliatesContact Us
Privacy PolicyPrivacy PolicyThe Metabolomics Society is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our website (the “Site”) and participate in interactive features such as the Forum. This Privacy Policy explains the type of information we may collect from you, and how we use it, process it, share it, and safeguard it. This Policy complies with the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR"). By using the Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to modify it at any time, and your continued use of the Site indicates your acceptance of any modifications.
The disclosures below relating to the collection, use, processing and/or sharing (“Processing Activities”) of information regarding an individual who is directly or indirectly identified or identifiable (“Personal Data”), apply to Processing Activities by any means, including hardcopy and electronic.
Personal Data We Obtain from You
Communications Intended for the Metabolomics Society - If you knowingly provide identifiable information to us by registering for the Forum or otherwise participating in a data collection instrument, we will use the information for the purpose for which it was collected. For example, we may ask you to take surveys and provide non-personally identifiable information about yourself such as gender, age, and volume or type of scientific research you conduct in order to improve Society membership or to understand our community’s needs. If you contact us to provide feedback or to ask a question, we record your personal information and the content of your communication so that we can respond to you effectively. We may also use this information to send you information about the Metabolomics Society or to contact you when necessary.
Content Submitted to the Forum – We make an interactive area of the Site called the Forum available to you and other members of the public. We store and may display content that you submit to the Forum, and when we do so we identify it with your username, city, state and the primary photo we ask you to upload to your Forum account. You are solely responsible for all content you submit, and all such content may be viewed by members of the public, whether they are registered users of the Forum or not. Please do not post any information or images that you do not want others to view. When participating in the Forum, you are required to comply with the Community Guidelines and other terms and conditions contained in the Society’s Forum User Agreement.
If you register for the Forum, you have the ability to choose your username and password. We recommend that you use a unique password for your account to prevent account theft. You are responsible for all activities that occur in connection with your password and account, including but not limited to selecting an appropriate and professional username, maintaining the confidentiality of your password and account information, and preventing others (including individuals whose Forum accounts have been terminated), to access the Forum using your account or username. You agree to notify This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it. immediately of any unauthorized use of your password or account information or any other breach of security.
Personal Data We Obtain from Third Party SourcesService Providers - As part of our Processing Activities, we may obtain certain Personal Data about you from third party service providers and payment processors, such as RegOnline, to perform services on our behalf. Some of these providers have access to Personal Data about you that we may not otherwise have (for example, when you sign up directly with that provider) and may share some or all these data with us. Some of our online services may allow you to register and login to those services through a third-party platform. When you login to our service through a third-party platform, you allow us to access and collect any Personal Data from your third-party platform account permitted under the settings and privacy statement of that platform.
Additional Personal Data - As part of our Processing Activities, we may receive additional Personal Data from third-party sources, such as public or private databases (for example, compilations of email or postal addresses), or companies or institutions that may sponsor or facilitate your participation in one of our programs, which we may also append to existing Personal Data.
Additional Uses of Personal Data
In addition to the uses described above, we may use your Personal Data for the purposes that follow. These uses may under certain circumstances be based on your consent, or may be necessary to fulfill our contractual commitments to you, to comply with legal requirements, or to serve our legitimate interests in the following operations:
• Conduct our operations and administer our offerings.• Contact you to respond to your requests or inquiries.• Provide you with newsletters, articles, service alerts or announcements, event invitations, and other information that we believe may be of interest to you.• Perform marketing, promotions and advertising, either directly or through third-parties.• Prevent, investigate, take action regarding or provide notice of fraud, unlawful or criminal activity or other misconduct.• Prevent, investigate, take action regarding or provide notice of security or technical issues, or unauthorized access to or use of Personal Data, the Site, or data systems.• Respond to court orders or other legal process, enforce our agreements, and meet legal obligations.
Data Retention
We will retain your Personal Data for as long as necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy unless a longer period is required under applicable law, or is needed to resolve disputes or protect our legal rights or otherwise to comply with legal obligations.Where we are processing Personal Data based on our legitimate interests, we generally will retain the data for a reasonable period of time based on the particular interest, taking into account the fundamental interests and the rights and freedoms of the data subjects.Where we are processing Personal Data based on your consent, we generally will retain the information for the period of time necessary to carry out the processing activities to which you consented, subject to your right, under certain circumstances, to have certain of your Personal Data erased (see “Your Rights” below).Where we are processing Personal Data based on the public interest, we generally retain the information for the period of time that continues to serve that interest.
How We Share and Disclose Personal Data
Although we never sell anyone’s Personal Data, we share your Personal Data with third parties in the ways described above and, in addition, we may share information as described below:
Service Providers - We share your Personal Data with third-party service providers that complete transactions or perform services on our behalf or for your benefit, such as:
• Payment and contribution processing• Customer relationship management (CRM) services• Marketing and analytics• Event registration and coordination• Course registration and administration• Enrollment verification• Research insights and analytics• System maintenance and security
Legal Process, Safety and Terms Enforcement - We may disclose your Personal Data to legal or government regulatory authorities as required by applicable law. We also disclose your Personal Data to third parties as required by applicable law in connection with claims, disputes or litigation, when otherwise required by applicable law, or if we determine its disclosure is necessary to protect the health, safety, rights or property of you, us or others, or to enforce our legal rights or contractual commitments that you have made.
International Data Transfers
We may transfer your Personal Data relying on appropriate or suitable safeguards or specific derogations recognized under data protection laws, including the GDPR. The European Commission has adopted standard data protection clauses, which provide safeguards for Personal Data transferred outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). We may use standard contractual clauses when transferring Personal Data from a country in the EEA to a country outside the EEA. If your Personal Data are affected, you can request a copy of our standard contractual clauses by contacting us as set forth in the Contact Us section below.
Information We CollectWe may collect Personal Data about you, or information that becomes Personal Data if combined with other information, when you visit or use the Sites or other online services. This information may be collected through the use of cookies, which are small data files placed on your computer or mobile device that allow us to collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with our Site or other online services. Some of these cookies are managed by us, while others are managed by third parties that we do not control. This information may also be collected through the use of other data collection technologies that embed graphic files in our Site and online services. These graphic files contain a unique identifier that enables us to recognize when someone has visited our website or online services or opened an email that we have sent.
You can control the use of certain cookies and similar technologies by:
• Opting out of targeted online advertising through advertising networks (please visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices/, http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/ or http://www.youronlinechoices.com for more information);
• Setting or amending your web browser controls to accept or refuse cookies (please visit your browser’s help menu for more information).
If you choose to reject certain cookies and similar technologies, you may still use our websites and online services, although your access to some functionality and features may be restricted.
Your RightsWe will provide you, upon your reasonable request, with information about whether we hold any of your Personal Data as part of our Processing Activities, to the extent required by and in accordance with applicable law. In certain cases, you may also have a right, with respect to your Personal Data collected and used in the Processing Activities, to:
• Correct or update any of your Personal Data that is inaccurate.• Restrict or limit the ways in which we use your Personal Data.• Object to the processing of your Personal Data.• Request the deletion of your Personal Data.• Obtain a copy of your Personal Data in an easily accessible format.
To submit a request, please email This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.. To avoid taking action regarding your Personal Data at the direction of someone other than you, we may ask you for information verifying your identity. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.
You have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing of your Personal Data as part of our Processing Activities, where our processing is solely based on your consent, subject to certain legal limitations. In some cases, you can do this by discontinuing use of the services involved in the Processing Activities. This would include by closing your online account with us and contacting us at This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it. to request that your Personal Data be deleted. If you withdraw your consent to the use or sharing of your Personal Data for the purposes set out in this Policy, you may not have access to all (or any) of the related services, and we might not be able to provide you all (or any) of the services. Please note that, in certain cases, we may continue to process your Personal Data after you have withdrawn consent and requested that we delete your Personal Data, if we have a legal basis to do so. For example, we may retain certain data if we need to do so to comply with an independent legal obligation, if we still need the data for the lawful purposes for which we obtained the data, or if it is necessary to do so to pursue our legitimate interest in keeping our services and operations safe and secure.If you have any complaints regarding our privacy practices, you have the right to make a complaint with your national data protection authority.
Opting Out of Communications from the SocietyYou may opt-out of receiving postal mail, e-mail and/or facsimile communications from the Metabolomics Society by either of the following means:
• Click on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any Metabolomics Society email.or• Send an email requesting to opt out of receiving postal mail, e-mail and/or facsimile communications to This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it..
We will take commercially reasonable steps to implement your opt-out request promptly; but you may still receive promotional information from the Metabolomics Society by postal mail for up to 60 days due to printing and mailing schedules, and up to 10 days for facsimile and e-mail.
Please note that this opt-out process does not apply to messages from the Metabolomics Society regarding your membership or organizational matters, such as nominations and awards.
Website Security
The Metabolomics Society uses commercially reasonable precautions to protect the security of your personal information using industry standard measures of protection, but absolute security cannot be guaranteed. It is up to you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and your computer. The Society is not liable for the transfer of any personal information resulting from corruption of storage media, power failures, riots, acts of vandalism, sabotage, or any other event beyond our reasonable control.
Links to Other SitesThe Site contains links to websites operated by parties other than the Metabolomics Society. The Society does not control these websites and is not responsible for their contents or privacy practices. We encourage you to read these websites’ privacy policies. Our inclusion of links does not imply any endorsement of the content on the websites or any association with their operators.
Contacting UsIf you have any questions about this Privacy Policy and GDPR Disclosures, you may contact the Metabolomics Society at This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it..
